

Leon Ingelse

Contact

▼ leoningelse@gmail.com

leoningel.github.io

github.com/Leoningel

Leon Ingelse

□ +31645341995

Languages

Dutch	Native
English	C2
Spanish	C1
Portuguese	B2

Computer skills

Python	4.5 yrs.
git	4.5 yrs.
SQL	3.5 yrs.
R	2 yrs.
F#	1.5 yrs.
Java	0.5 yrs.

Biography

As a mathematician, I am analytical, critical, and a natural problem-solver. As an AI researcher, I have developed a wide range of technical skills and gained extensive experience in both independent work and group projects. Although I have a technical background, my social and communicative skills will surprise you. My curiosity for the unknown has taken me around the world, allowing me to engage with different cultures and diverse worldviews. I speak 4 languages at a professional level.

Altogether, I am independent, sociable, reliable, resourceful, positive, and critical. I am also a quick learner and a transparent communicator. Feel free to reach out for a chat!

Work experience

Data analyst

Onja | Toamasina (Madagascar) - Remote

03/2024 - Ongoing

Technical Writer

Dots & Lines | Remote | Part-time freelancer

06/2024 - Ongoing

02/2021 - 10/2023

Research assistant

LASIGE | Lisbon | Remote

Funded by FCT – Supervised by Prof. Fonseca

Main achievements: See publications and Genetic Engine

Research journalist

05/2023 - 11/2023

Global Voices | Remote

Works: Al usage by Dutch government - Colonialism in Portugal

Software engineer and Data scientist

02/2019 - 08/2020

Impact Institute | Amsterdam

Research & Development team. Main achievement: Global Impact Database.

High school tutor

OVER huiswerkbegeleiding | Amsterdam

09/2014 - 01/2018

Side Jobs

Besides the above, I have done numerous side jobs, e.g., sales agent, receptionist, cleaner, cook, bartender, dish washer, grape picker, and cashier, amongst others.

Education

Data Science (M.Sc.) | GPA: 18 (/20)

09/2020 - 09/2022

University of Lisbon

Al • ML • Explainable Al • Genetic Programming • Feature Learning • Databases Thesis: "Optimisation of Feature Learning through Grammar-Guided GP".

Mathematics (B.Sc.) | GPA: 7.06 (/10)

09/2014 - 01/2019

University of Amsterdam

Algebra • Real analysis • Number theory • Topology • Statistics

Thesis: "p-Adic numbers and the local-global principle".

International Development (Minor)

University of Amsterdam

09/2018 - 01/2019

09/2016 - 12/2016

Spanish (Minor)

Pontificia Católica Universidad de Chile

Selected publications (see all)

Ingelse, Leon, et al. Comparing Individual Representations in Grammar-Guided Genetic Programming for Glucose Prediction in People with Diabetes. GECCO workshop (2023).

Ingelse, Leon, and Fonseca, Alcides, (2023). *Domain-Aware Feature Learning with Grammar-Guided Genetic Programming*. EuroGP 2023 Proceedings. Springer Nature.

Ingelse, Leon, et al. (2022). *Personalised Gait Recognition for People with Neurological Conditions*. Sensors 22.11 (2022): 3980.

Projects

Writer

Besides my research writings, I write opinion pieces, write for the newsletter of \underline{VvdO} , write promotional texts for \underline{LRC} , and write poetry.

Trumpet player

Candy Flip | Lisbon

Body Painter

Risquinhos de Leon | Lisbon

Boulder Gym | Co-founder & Manager

Floresta de Baobás | Lisbon

Student Ambassador | Leader Creative Committee

International office University of Amsterdam

09/2023 - Ongoing

09/2022 - Ongoing

06/2023 - Ongoing

06/2023 - 02/2024

02/2017 - 08/2017

Volunteering

Distributor

Fruta Feia | Lisbon

Cook

Zona Franca nos Anjos | Lisbon

Coordinator

Buurtbuik West | Amsterdam

Football trainer

Escuela de Fútbol Clotario Blest | Santiago de Chile

09/2023 - Ongoing

09/2023 - 02/2024

10/2019 - 09/2020

09/2016 - 12/2016

Leon Ingelse